<resources>
    <string name="app_name">AlgoPlay</string>
    <string name="stack"> A stack is a container of objects that are inserted and removed according to the last-in first-out (LIFO) principle. In the pushdown stacks only two operations are allowed: push the item into the stack, and pop the item out of the stack. A stack is a limited access data structure - elements can be added and removed from the stack only at the top. push adds an item to the top of the stack, pop removes the item from the top. </string>
    <string name="queue">A queue is a container of objects (a linear collection) that are inserted and removed according to the first-in first-out (FIFO) principle. An excellent example of a queue is a line of students in the food court of the UC. New additions to a line made to the back of the queue, while removal (or serving) happens in the front. In the queue only two operations are allowed enqueue and dequeue. Enqueue means to insert an item into the back of the queue, dequeue means removing the front item. </string>
    <string name="linear">Linear search algorithm finds a given element in a list of elements with O(n) time complexity where n is total number of elements in the list. This search process starts comparing search element with the first element in the list. If both are matched then result is element found otherwise search element is compared with the next element in the list. Repeat the same until search element is compared with the last element in the list, if that last element also doesnt match, then the result is Element not found in the list. That means, the search element is compared with element by element in the list.</string>
    <string name="binary">Binary search is a fast search algorithm with run-time complexity of Ο(log n). This search algorithm works on the principle of divide and conquer. For this algorithm to work properly, the data collection should be in the sorted form.Binary search looks for a particular item by comparing the middle most item of the collection. If a match occurs, then the index of item is returned. If the middle item is greater than the item, then the item is searched in the sub-array to the left of the middle item. Otherwise, the item is searched for in the sub-array to the right of the middle item. This process continues on the sub-array as well until the size of the subarray reduces to zero.</string>
    <string name="bubble">Bubble Sort is a simple algorithm which is used to sort a given set of n elements provided in form of an array with n number of elements. Bubble Sort compares all the element one by one and sort them based on their values.If the given array has to be sorted in ascending order, then bubble sort will start by comparing the first element of the array with the second element, if the first element is greater than the second element, it will swap both the elements, and then move on to compare the second and the third element, and so on.
If we have total n elements, then we need to repeat this process for n-1 times.
It is known as bubble sort, because with every complete iteration the largest element in the given array, bubbles up towards the last place or the highest index, just like a water bubble rises up to the water surface.Sorting takes place by stepping through all the elements one-by-one and comparing it with the adjacent element and swapping them if required.
</string>
    <string name="insertion">Insertion sort is the sorting mechanism where the sorted array is built having one item at a time. The array elements are compared with each other sequentially and then arranged simultaneously in some particular order. The analogy can be understood from the style we arrange a deck of cards. This sort works on the principle of inserting an element at a particular position, hence the name Insertion Sort.</string>

</resources>
